Montreal Superior Court mss., 1718-1739 LMC 1769
Lilly Library
Montreal Superior Court mss.
1718-1739
1973
Lilly Library
Montreal Superior Court
LMC 1769
1 Box 1 standard
The Montreal Superior Court mss., 1718-1739, are certified typescripts of documents no. 9068-9085, 9470-9488, 9763-9777, 11333-11346, 11885-11894, 11900-11916, 1238-12244, 14112- 14133, 15229, 15314-15328, and 15330-15341 registered in the Montreal Court superieure and preserved in the Archives judiciaires du district de Montreal.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Historical Note
The documents relate to the French period in Indiana and are concerned particularly with the Ouiatanon and Miami posts between the years 1718-1739. The Montreal Superior Court made these typescripts as exact text reproductions of the original documents in the 1950's. The original documents preside in the Archives judiciaires du district de Montreal.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged numerically by document number and chronologically by registration date.
Scope and Content Note
The documents consist of permits to trade with the Indians, permits to travel and carry provisions to the posts, and contracts of boatmen and others, who felt the necessity of putting their obligations into writing before departing on their journeys.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1973
Montreal Superior Court
- Documents no. 9068-9085, 1718-1721 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 9470-9488, 1722-1725 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 9763-9777, 1723-1726 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 11333-11346, 1723-1726 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 11885-11894, 1725-1726 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 11900-11916, 1727-1733 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 12238-12244, 1726-1729 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 14112-14133, 1730-1736 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 15229-15328, 1737-1738 (Box 1)
- Documents no. 15330-15341, 1738-1739 (Box 1)